Guide to the Rice University Student Affairs Committee Records, UA 173, 1963-1983 UA 173
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Student Affairs Committee Records
1963-1983
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 173
0.75 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Minutes, memoranda, reports, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Committee on Student Affairs.
Organizational Note
The Committee on Student Affairs (later named the Student Activities Committee and then again named the Committee on Student Affairs) was a policy making committee which was formed to regulate undergraduate student activities and aspects of student life on Rice campus. On April 1, 1965, the Student Affairs Committee was re-formulated into a Student Activities Committee, along with, a new committee the Committee of Undergraduate Affairs was to coordinate student affairs with attention to undergraduate student life. The committee was intended to be an excecutive policy-determining committee with no student members. The Student Activities Committee formed policy on issues such as student discipline, alcohol, and dorm rules. However, by July 1965, membership of the committee had changed to include students. In 1975, the committee returned to its former name - the Committee on Student Affairs.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the minutes, memoranda, reports, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Committee on Student Affairs.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 1 stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Box 2 stored off-site at Iron Mountain and requires 48-hour notice for retrieval. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection were transferred to the Woodson Research Center from the Committee on Student Affairs.
Index Terms
Subjects
College students -- Texas; Universities and colleges
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Rice University Student Affairs Committee records, 1963-1983
  - Minutes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Minutes, Memos, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Memos, Correspondence, Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Memos, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Handbook of Policies, Rules, and Regulations Affecting Undergraduate Life, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pending Matters, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, Appointments, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Memos, Appointments, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, Reports, Appointments, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, Memos, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)